David M. Stowe Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Sermons, Lectures, Talks by DMS, 1942-1999; Series II
  - Lectures/Talks
    - Early Lecture/Talks, 1940s
      - Seminary talks incl: "Truth in the Inward Parts";"Reason for Our Hope"; "Christianity and World Order", Plymouth House, Berkeley, CA, 1943-1944 (Box 14, Folder 86-89)
      - Bible Talks; general religion talks incl: "Christians & Culture", 1945-1948 (Box 14, Folder 90-91)
      - Incl. Yenching Easter Talk: "The Christian Understanding of Love"; "Mission Theology of the 1960s"; "Mission and the United Church", 1950-1960s (Box 14, Folder 92-93)
    - Berkeley Talks: General Religion/Theology
      - File A 5 - 148, 1950s (Box 14, Folder 94-101)
      - File A 150, 192, 194, [n.n.], 1950s (Box 15, Folder 102-103)
    - Mid-century Lectures/Talks, 1960s- 1970s
      - Incl. "World Missions: Heritage and Horizons" [Television Address]; "Mission in the Ecumenical Church"; "Christian Missions in Social Revolution", 1960-1964 (Box 15, Folder 104-106)
      - Lectures incl: "The Shape of Our Calling to Missions"; "A Time to Gather"; and "Missions in Crisis: The Christian's Calling"; Asilomar Conference: "Mission: All Christians' Calling", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 107-108)
      - Lectures on Affluence & Poverty, Hawaii; "Two Centuries -- One Mission", Commencement address at Pacific School of Religion; "Why Mission Today?", 1966-1967 (Box 15, Folder 109-110)
      - "The Church, the Word, and the Nations", Woodstock, 1967 Mar.29 -Apr 1 (Box 15, Folder 111)
      - "Christianity Among Faiths", Fayetteville, Arkansas, 1967 Jun 17-23 (Box 15, Folder 112-114)
      - "Who Shall Separate Us?"; "Ecumenicity and Evangelism" - lecture series at Fuller Theological Seminary, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 115)
      - United Methodist Church Lectures; "Changing Patterns of Missionary Service" at Second Triennial Assembly NCC, DOM; "Compassion" at dedication of Church World Service building, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 116)
      - Deering Lectures; "Religious Dimensions of Fund-Raising" (for national Catholic Development Conference); "Theology of Development - Perspectives from Mao Tse-tung", 1968, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 117)
      - "God's Left Hand and Right Hand", Biennial Meeting of the Near East Mission, UCBWM, Istanbul; "New World, One World" - Inaugural address at UCBWM, 1970 Jun, Nov (Box 16, Folder 118)
      - "Florida Lectures", 1970s (Box 16, Folder 119)
      - "Future of Mission/Future of the Christian Faith"; "Man's World, God's World"; Keynote address for annual meeting of UCBWM; "Mission: Interaction Around the World"; Address at Montreat; Address at Ursinus, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 120)
      - Lectures Incl: "Evangelism in an Ecosystem"; and "Sunday Morning in Peking"; "One Family, Many Faiths"; Keynote address for annual meeting of UCBWM, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 121)
      - Misc. Notes for Lectures, incl. Keynote address for annual meeting of UCBWM: "Mission Policy for Ecumenopolis"; "Dimensions of our Fellowship"; "World Responsibilities for American Christians?", 1973 (Box 16, Folder 122)
      - "Contemporary Experience and Salvation", Oklahoma; "A Christian Looks at Hunger", Kansas City, 1973 -1974 (Box 16, Folder 123)
      - Addresses for UCBWM annual meetings, incl. "God's View of the Population Explosion" (1974); "Ecumenism, Pluralism & the Future of American Experience", 1974-1976 (Box 16, Folder 124)
      - "The Future of the Western Missionary Enterprise," Mission Policy in Search of New Directions" - Chicago Mission Institute; "Have You Eaten?", 1976 (Box 16, Folder 124)
      - Address for UCBWM annual meeting: "Imperatives and Opportunities for World Ministries, 1977-1984"; misc. notes for lectures (Box 16, Folder 125)
      - Address for UCBWM annual meeting: "One World - One Family - One Lord"; "Jewish-Christian-Muslim Forum; misc. notes for lectures, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 126)
      - Address for UCBWM annual meeting:" The Power of Partnership"; "Mission: Interaction Around the World", 1979 (Box 17, Folder 127)
      - Address for UCBWM annual meeting: "Challenges to World Ministries"; "Christian Word in Hungry World", 1980 (Box 17, Folder 128)
      - Address for UCBWM annual meeting:"The Future of a Heritage"; "Mission & the World Economy"; "Bridging Faiths, Cultures, and Nations", 1981 (Box 17, Folder 129)
      - Address for UCBWM annual meeting:"World Ministries and World Peace";"Missionaries of Peace"; and "The Black Church & Third World Responsibility"; "Our Mission Covenant Today", 1982-1983 (Box 17, Folder 130)
      - "Mission in International Context"; and "The Integrity of the Faith and Witness to the World", 1984 (Box 17, Folder 131)
      - "Untitled"; undated lectures incl. "The Great Missionary Debate", 1998, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 132-133)
    - 1980s-1990s Lectures
      - "Report on the Melbourne Conference on World Mission and Evangelism"; "Are Christians Good Investors?", 1980,1981 (Box 17, Folder 134)
      - Misc. lecture notes; Hugh Vernon White Lecture, 1982-1983 (Box 17, Folder 135-137)
      - Bartlett Lectures: "The Mission of the Church from the Present to the Year 2,000", Silver Lake, Cuyahoga, Ohio, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 138)
      - Notes for Talk at Montclair's Women's Guild; "Theological Reflections on the Future of Mission", 1986-1987 (Box 17, Folder 139-140)
      - Yale Divinity School Bartlett Lecture: "China and the Protestant Ethic"; "The Division of Overseas Ministries - From Then Till Now", 1989, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 141)
      - Incl.remarks on 50th Anniversary of Ministry, Cresskill, UCC; "Indigenization of the Church in China", 1993-1995 (Box 17, Folder 142-145)
  - Records of Speaking Engagements
    - Early Speaking Engagements, 1940s- 1950s
      - Incl. "Can Christianity Live with Communism?"; First Congregational Church, Berkeley, California talks, 1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 146)
      - Incl: Connecticut Conference of Congregational Christian Churches; Garden City Community Church, New York; and The Ohio Conference of Congregational Churches; CBS News Radio Church of the Air; Yale Divinity School, 1958 -1959 (Box 18, Folder 147-151)
    - Mid-century Speaking Engagements, 1960s- 1970s
      - Incl: Commission on Church Ministry; Congregational Christian Temple, Norfolk, Virginia; and First Congregational Church, Binghamton, New York, 1960 Jan-Mar (Box 18, Folder 153)
      - Incl: Carleton College; Joint National Youth Council; United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A., New York City; and at United Church Board of World Ministries annual meeting: "Mission in Ecumenical History, 1960 Apr-1963 (Box 19, Folder 154-158)
      - Incl:Canadian Council of Churches; Silver Bay Conference on the Christian World Mission; Commission on Ecumenical Mission and Relations; and First Congregational Church Montclair, New Jersey, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 159-160)
      - Incl: First Congregational Church of Long Beach; Community Church of Beirut; Pacific Coast Missionary Education Conferences; Southwest Conference on Missions, 1965-1967 (Box 20, Folder 161-164)
      - Incl: Catholic Inter-American Cooperation Program; Riverside Church; Cross Memorial Lecture, Greeley, CO, 1968-1979 (Box 20, Folder 165-168)
    - Later Speaking Engagements, 1980s-1990s
      - Incl. Church of the Apostles, Lancaster, PA; and Madison Avenue Baptist Church, New York, New York; Yale Divinity School, 1984-1990 (Box 20, Folder 169-172)
      - Incl. Hillsborough Centre Congregational Church, Tenafly, NJ, 1994-1999 (Box 20, Folder 173-175)
- DMS Writings, 1940-2001; Series III
  This series documents Stowe's extensive writings on historical, missions-related, and theological topics. In his later years, he wrote many entries for reference works on ABCFM missions and missionaries.
  - Bibliography
    - List of works by DMS, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Books/ booklets / pamphlets
    - "The Conquest of Inner Space"; "Heritage and Horizons," "Remembrance and Renewal," Into All the World Together", 1958, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 2-3)
    - "What on Earth is the Church Doing," High Fellowship Helps; "A New Era in World Missions," Creating and Renewing the Church, Program Book, 1961, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - "What is Christian Witness," "A New Look at an Old Subject," "Why Mission Today," "Vellore News", 1962,1963 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - When Faith Meets Faith, chapters from book, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 6-7)
    - "Why Mission Today," "Vellore News," "Credibility in Evangelism"; "An Experiment in Dialogue: Christian and Chinese", 1967 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - "God's Left Hand and Right Hand"; "New World One World," Inaugural Address, UCBWM, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - "The Fellowship of Prayer," Lenten Season, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - "Year 175: A Brief History of the United Church Board for World Missions,", 1984 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - "Look Inside,"; "Six Trillion Five Hundred Billion Dollars?"; "Where do You Stand?"; "The American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions" (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Portions of books: chapters
    - "The Old Testament and the Christian;" "The Public Worship of God," Some Fell Into Good Ground: Sermons Preached in the Congregational Churches of North China 1947-1948 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - "A New Era in World Missions," Creating and Renewing the Church - Program Book, 1961-1962 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - "Foreign Missions in Social Revolution," Christianity Amid Rising Men and Nations, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - "A Fellowship of Christians in the World," The Church in Our World: A Study of the Nature and Mission of the UCC, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - "Strategy: The Church's Response to What God is Doing," Protestant Crosscurrents in Mission; Joseph J. Blomjous, "Ecclesial Dimensions of Mission Responsibility," Comments: David M. Stowe and Thomas E. Quigley, The Word in the Third World, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 17-18)
    - "World Responsibilities for American Christians?," Four Faces of Christian Ministry: Essays in Honor of A.Dale Fiers; "Mission in the '80s: An Assessment of the Future," Mission Handbook: North American Protestant Ministries Overseas, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 19-20)
    - "The Poor and the Oppressed," Call to Global Mission; "Martin Luther aus der Sicht der Vereinigten Kirche Christi," Gott Über Alle Dinge; "Process Theology," UCC Theologies, 1982, 1983, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 21-23)
  - Contributions to reference works
    - Dictionary of Christianity in America (IVP)
      - Author's guidelines and entries A-Z, 1987,1988 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Biographical Dictionary of Christian Missions (MacMillan)
      - Notecards and instructions, 1993-1995 (Box 22, Folder 25)
      - Abeel, David; Aea, Hezekiah and Debora; Alexander, William Patterson; Allen, David Oliver; Andrews, Lorrin; Anderson, Rufus; Armstrong, Richard (Box 22, Folder 26-32)
      - Ball, Dyer; Barton, James Levi; Bingham, Hiram, Sybil Moseley, Hiram Jr.; Bishop, Artemas; Bliss, Daniel; Bliss, Issac Grout; Boudinot, Elias (Box 22, Folder 33-39)
      - Bridgman, Elijah Coleman; Clark, Ephram W; Coan, Titus; Cochran, Joseph Gallup; Dwight, Harrison Gray Otis; Evarts, Jeremiah (Box 23, Folder 40-45)
      - Fisk, Pliny; Goodell, William; Green, Samuel Fiske; Gulick, Luther Halsey, Louisa Mitchell Lewis; Gulick, Orramel H., Anna Eliza Clark; Gulick, Peter Johnson, Fanny Hinckley Thomas (Box 23, Folder 46-51)
      - Hall, Gordon; Hamlin, Cyrus and Henrietta; Hoy, William Edwin; Hume, Robert Wilson; Judd, Gerrit; King, Jonas; Kingsbury, Cyrus (Box 23, Folder 52-58)
      - Laubach, Frank Charles; Lindley, Daniel; Lohr, Oskar T.; Lyman, Rev. David B; Lyons, Lorenzo; McDowell, Henry Curtis; Merrick, James Lyman; Miner, Luella; Morse, Jedediah (Box 23, Folder 59-67)
      - Nessima, Joseph Hardy; Newell, Samuel; Obookiah, Henry (Opukahaia); Parsons, Levi; Patrick, Mary Mills; Perkins, Justin; Porter, Lucius Chopin (Box 23, Folder 68-74)
      - Richards, William; Riggs, Elias; Schauffler, William Gottlieb; Scudder, John; Shattuck, Corinna; Smith, Arthur Henderson; Smith, Eli; Spaulding, Levi (Box 23, Folder 75-82)
      - Thurston, Asa; Tyler, Josiah; White, Hugh Vernon; Williams, William Frederick; Winslow, Harriet Wadsworth Lathrop; Winslow, Miron; Wu, Y.T. (Wu Yao- tsung) (Box 23, Folder 83-89)
    - American National Bibliography
      - Instruction Materials, 1993, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 90)
      - Abeel, David; Barton, James Levi; Erickson, Charles Telford; Fiske, Fidelia; Goodell, William; Gulick, Luther Halsey (Box 24, Folder 91-96)
      - Hall, Gordon; Harbaugh, Henry; Riggs, Stephen; Schauffler, William; Smith, Judson; Woolman, John (Box 24, Folder 97-102)
  - Forewords to books
    - Foreword to The Church in Angola by L.W. Henderson (Box 24, Folder 103)
  - Articles in journals
    - "Piers Plowman," "A Fourteenth Century Social Gospel" in Christendom, 1943-1944 (Box 24, Folder 104-105)
    - "An Open Door in China" in The Missionary Herald At Home and Abroad; "A Red-Eyed Look at Education" in Shattuck Alumni Magazine, 1951, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 106-107)
    - "Is Drinking a Religious Issue?"; "Faith in Action on a College Campus";"American Board Yearbook" in Advance; "Why Foreign Missions?" in Mission Today, 1955-1958 (Box 24, Folder 108-109)
    - "Christian Leadership on Mission Fields" in Minister's Quarterly; "Overseas Mission Program Reviewed"; "Church's Responsibility for Gifted Youth," in Advance, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 110-111)
    - "It's his yen to make an impact on a new frontier"; "Are we really facing the facts on Red China?"; "Can man's desire to heal inspire his creative powers?"; "Is any kind of religion a good thing?"; "Ambassadors wear grey flannel---and dungarees"; "Ralph, what are you doing out there?, in Youth, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 112)
    - "During the 10 years of Communist Rule in China...What's been happening to the Church?" in United Church Herald; "Inter-play of Missions and Theology," in Minister's Quarterly, 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 113-114)
    - "Red China: Challenge to U.S. Policy," in Christianity and Crisis; "Should the United States change its policy toward the People's Repulic of China?" in Social Action; "Missionary Hymns---the Music of Our Mission," in Mission Today, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 115-116)
    - "American Board Observes 150th Anniversary" in United Church Herald; "Heritage and Horizons in Missions" in The Christian Century and The Missionary, 1960- 1961 (Box 25, Folder 117-118)
    - "Anti-Semitism Response Letter" in Social Action "Of God, whose purpose spans the ages..." (poem/prayer) in Youth; "The 150th Anniversary of the first sailing of American missionaries" in United Church Herald, 1961-1962 (Box 25, Folder 119-120)
    - "Reader's Response: What Delhi Achieved" in The Christian Century, Untitled article in Task Force; "Dietrich Bonhoeffer: Prophet of the 21st Century?" in Near East School of Theology Quarterly; "The Reluctant Missionary" in Youth, 1962-1963 (Box 25, Folder 121-123)
    - "American Mission" in World Congregationalism; "From the Beginning, Global" and "Authority and Mission" in Children's Religion; "Pertinent Reading on the New Nations" in Social Action; "Can the Church Make a Difference In the World?" and "Square on Target" in United Church Herald; "Partnership in Mission" in Christian Mission Digest, 1963-1964 (Box 25, Folder 124-125)
    - "What about Mainland China?" in The Christian Century; "The Church in Communist China" in United Church Herald; "The Bible and the Laity in Mission" in The Church Woman, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 126-128)
    - "The Shape of Our Calling to Mission" in World Outlook; "Community and Contrast in Mission" in Occasional Bulletin of Missionary Research; "Survey - North America" in International Review of Missions; "Christ and the Faiths of Men" in The Church Woman; "China Today--- Communist Impact and Christian Responsibility" in World Outlook; "Credibility and Evangelism" in World Vision Magazine; "Vatican II on Mission: A Protestant View" in Overseas Mission Review, 1966-1967 (Box 25, Folder 129-130)
    - "A Perspective on the Church Growth Question" in Information Service; "The World's Religion" in Class Mate; "Why Mission Today?" in The Christian; "Amateurism and Sentimentality Unacceptable in Today's World" in Approach; "The Emphasis is Ecumenical" in The Presbyterian Outlook; "Can Christianity Survive the World Council of Churches?" in Pulpit Digest, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 131-133)
    - "Formes changeantes du service missionnaire," in Eglise Vivante; "Changing Patterns of Missionary Service in Today's World" in Occasional Bulletin; "New Guidelines for Missionary Service" in Information Service; "The Statistics---the Image" in Response; "Oaxtepec: Of Message and Mission" in Bible Society Record; "Is Mission Work Over?" in Lutheran Standard; "Foreign Missions Today: A Spent Force?" in The Baptist Student, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 134-135)
    - "Hallelujahs for Hungry Lives," "Easter Witnesses," "China: the Church," in United Church Herald; "COCU and N.C.C.: How the New Church Would Affect Conciliarism" in Christian Century; "Perspectives on Development from Mao Tse-Tung" in China Notes; "Changing Patterns of Missionary Service in Today's World " in Practical Theology; "What Conversion Means" in World Call, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 136-137)
    - "Mission 1970's: End of Anchronism" in Encounter; "Brother, Are You Saved?" in Event (includes audio tape), 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 138-140)
    - "China: Model for the World?" in Magazine for the United Church of Christ Family; "Christians Challenge the Rabbi's Response" in Worldview; "Christian Mission" in Ecumenical Trends; "Toward a Process Theology of Mission" in Encounter, 1977-1979 (Box 26, Folder 141-144)
    - "Toward a Process Theology of Mission," Occasional Bulletin, Jul. 1980 (Box 26, Folder 145)
    - "What Did Melbourne Say?" in Missiology: An International Review; "From Haystack to the World" in Historical Intelligencer; "Defining Mission as We Approach 2000 A.D., United Church of Christ; "The Poor and the Oppressed," background papers to the document: Call to Global Mission, 1981-1982 (Box 26, Folder 146-147)
    - "A New Perspective on the World Christian Mission" in Missiology: An International Review; "A Theology for Christian Mission" in Inside/Out; "A Theological Critique of U.C.C. Ecclessiology" in Historical Intelligencer, 1984-1986 (Box 26, Folder 148-150)
    - "Theological Reflections on the Future of Mission A Mission Executive's Perspective" in Missiology; "Future of the Missionary" in Tripod; "Modernization and Resistance: Theological Implications for Mission" in International Bulletin, 1987, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 151-152)
    - "China and the Protestant Ethic" in Reflections; "Background for an Apology to Native Hawaiian People" in New Conversations; "Living Music, Living God " in Creative Transformations, 1990-1995 (Box 27, Folder 153-155)
    - "My Pilgrimage in Mission" in International Bulletin of Missionary Research; "'A Light to the Nations': The Mind and Heart of David M. Stowe," (selections of DMS writings published posthumously by Charles and Elizabeth Hambrick-Stowe) in Prism, 1996, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 156-157)
  - Newsletter Contributions
    - General
      - "Towards a Process Theology of Mission," News Letter, Dec. 1978 (Box 27, Folder 158)
    - Whole Earth Newsletter
      - Bibliography of messages (Box 27, Folder 159)
      - Executive Vice President Messages, 1970-1977 (Box 27, Folder 160-167)
      - Executive Vice President Messages, 1978-1982 (Box 28, Folder 168-172)
  - Book Reviews
    - Reviews of books by Varg, Rosengrant, Allen, Kitagawa, Jones, Carden, Thomas, McGavran, Bush, 1958-1971 (Box 28, Folder 173-178)
    - Reviews of books by Latukefu, Fairbank, Ronning, Trexler, Scherer, Taylor, Neusner, Betto, 1974-1989 (Box 28, Folder 179-181)
    - Reviews of books by Bonk, Henderson, Westmeier, England, Moorhouse, 1990-1999 (Box 28, Folder 182-185)
  - Papers written as student
    - Divine Goodness: A Study of the Unity of Metaphysical and Moral Perfection in God (abstract of thesis), 1940 (Box 28, Folder 186)
    - "A Life of Paul"; "Whence the Dynamic of the Pre-War Social Gospel?", 1940 (Box 195, Folder 1-2)
    - Jesus papers; "The Nature of Religion"; "Paul's Conception of the Church and Ministry"; "The Contributions of Baron Von Hugel to the Problem of Religious Knowledge", 1940-1943, 1951 (Box 195, Folder 3-6)
    - "Luther and Reason"; "The Problem of Religious Knowledge"; Philosophy of History class; "Pragmatism and Theology"; "La Follette and Roosevelt, to 1909", 1951 -1952, n.d. (Box 196, Folder 7-11)
  - Miscellaneous writings
    - News Brief: Amagisanso, The South East Asia Journal of Theology; News Brief: Beruit, Reformatorische Theologie Fuer Heute; "O God, Whose Purpose Spans the Ages," (poem) TUNEIN; "Fit Me into Your Future" (poem); "The Beginning of a Mission," (statement), 1963-1983 (Box 28, Folder 187)
    - Reports to UCBWM Board of Directors; travel reports; statements and papers on theology and mission policy, 1971-1987 (Box 28, Folder 188-190)
    - "Process Theology," Theological Ferment in the United Church of Christ - Six Essays, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 191)
    - Incl. letters to the editor of Advance, Christianity Today, 1956,1989 (Box 28, Folder 192)
- Drafts, Notes, Sources for Proposed Board History, 1812-1980s; Series IV
  Following his retirement in 1985, Stowe was deeply engaged in gathering material for and beginning to write a comprehensive history of the ABCFM and UCBWM. This series contains his outlines and some drafts of chapters for the work, which was never completed.
  - Documents/notes re. Board history
    - Board origins: Charge to first missionaries; Charter and By-Laws; "The Haystack," a poem by N.V. Tilak; "Highlights from UCBWM" (timeline), 1812-1911, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1-5)
    - Articles: incl. re. Cotton Mather, UCC Historical Theology from Historical Intelligencer, "The Missionary's New Mission," Newsweek, 1963-1984 (Box 29, Folder 6-8)
    - Re. "Re-thinking Missions", UCBWM "Purposes", 1930s, 1970s (Box 29, Folder 9-10)
  - Drafts/Project Notes
    - Draft: Chapter on American Indians; Draft: Chapter III; Chapter IV, "Enterprise Takes Shape" (Box 29, Folder 11-16)
    - Index and summary; general notes for project; Chapter outlines (Box 30, Folder 17-28)
    - Alphabetical sequence of notes and collected items: A - M (Box 189, Folder 1-5)
    - Alphabetical sequence of notes and collected items: N-W (Box 190, Folder 1-3)
  - Education
    - Euphrates College; International Universities (various); Whitman College (Oregon) (Box 30, Folder 29-31)
  - Missionary personalities
    - Armstrong, Richard - Hawaii; Chamberlain, Capt. David - Hawaii; Hoy, Gertrude - China, Japan, Korea; Hume, Robert Allen - India; Newell, Harriet - India; Obookiah, Henry - Hawaii (Box 31, Folder 32-37)
    - Regions / people groups
      - Africa (Box 31, Folder 38)
      - American Indians, incl. at Stockbridge (Box 31, Folder 39-42)
      - China, incl. Foochow Mission (Box 31, Folder 43-47)
      - Hawaii (Box 32, Folder 48-59)
      - Hawaii (Box 33, Folder 60-62)
      - India/ Ceylon (Box 33, Folder 63-68)
      - Japan (Box 33, Folder 69-70)
      - Micronesia (Box 33, Folder 71-76)
      - Near East Mission (Box 33, Folder 77)
      - Near East Mission (Box 34, Folder 78-90)
      - Sri Lanka: Church Mission, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 91)
- Resource Files: ABCFM/UCBWM Documents, 1806-1996; Series V
  This series contains resources that Stowe compiled to assist him in writing his proposed history of the ABCFM and UCBWM. A comprehensive set of printed missionary circular letters provides a valuable overview of ABCFM/UCBWM mission activity, especially from the 1940s to the 1980s. Reports and documentation from the many Board meetings that Stowe attended also provide a good overview of issues and events.